Nicolas Rodriguez

🕈 San Francisco, United States 🛮 nicolasrdrgz@protonmail.com 🛘 +33618431698 🛅 in/nicolasrdrgz 🕳 nrdrgz.github.io

SUMMARY

Full Stack Data profile with 5+ years of experience on a high-performing analytics and data science teams working closely with business. Open to work as a Data contributor or Team Lead, based in San Francisco or Los Angeles, in Aerospace, Transport, Energy or AI industries.

EXPERIENCE

Data Manager and Team Lead

Voodoo

January 2022 - present, Paris, France

- Built from scratch and led an international team of 6 Data Full stack profiles, Junior to Senior, working with Growth business unit.
- · Led by example: Data Engineering with Airflow DAGs, API pulls, Python, Redshift, S3, AWS Services. Data Analysis with DBT, Tableau, SQL.
- · Technical Project management, mix between defining strategic goals and hands-on operations.
- · Communication with C levels to influence strategic decision-making and monitor north star metrics.

Analytics Engineer

Voodoo

July 2020 - January 2022, Paris, France

- · Data Full Stack role. Building models, tables, analyses and tools used by 600+ people for a \$800M revenue portfolio.
- Data Engineering operations dealing with a 2B events per day database. From API calls into AWS S3, Redshift and Athena, with Airflow DAGs.
- Data Science operations predicting future user revenue with Machine Learning models (XGBoost) achieving an accuracy of 85% to help Growth business operations. Develop analysis methods to evaluate Machine learning algorithms.
- Data Analytics operations working hand in hand with the business, building intermediate table with DBT, final dashboards and tools with Tableau. Statistical data analysis of AB-testing.

Data Consultant

Simon Kucher & Partners

January 2020 - July 2020, Paris, France

- · Facilitated stakeholder workshops and progress meetings to align project objectives using JIRA and Asana.
- · Data science & Machine learning projects to maximise pricing and portfolio value for various clients (energy, transport).

Graduate Research Associate

Aerospace System Design Laboratory

January 2018 - December 2019, Atlanta, USA

- Project in collaboration with NASA: conceptual design of a hybrid propulsion architecture for regional aircraft (50 passengers).
- Project in collaboration with NATO: optimization software and models for interventions and deployments of humanitarian aid.
- Development of a machine learning model to perform offline prediction of flight landing distances for multiple aircrafts.

EDUCATION

M.Sc., Aerospace Engineering and Data Science

Georgia Institute of Technology · Atlanta, USA · 2018-2019 · GPA 4/4

- Main subjects: General Physics, Advanced Mathematics, Machine Learning, Optimization, Business Management, Advanced Design Method.
- Master thesis: Improvement of Landing Safety by Machine Learning. Project in collaboration with Air Line companies. Training of Random Forest and Neural Network models over thousands of flight hours to predict aircraft landing distance.

M.Sc., Aerospace Engineering

ISAE Supaero · Toulouse, France · 2016-2020

· Main subjects: General Physics, Advanced Mathematics, Propulsion, Space Mechanics, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning.

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

Python, SQL, Java, C, C#, VBA, DBT, Tableau, Looker, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS Redshift, AWS Services, GCP, Snowflake, Airflow, Databricks, Data Engineering, Data Science, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Deep Learning.

Management and Communication Skills:

Team and Project Management, Strong analytical mindset, Excellent communication to technical and non technical audiences, Agile/Scrum methodologies, Data governance and compliance.

Specialized Expertise:

Mobile app growth and attribution expert (MMP, Apple SKAdNetwork)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Resume Chatbot using LLM and RAG

• Streamlit based application using ChatGPT API and RAG to offer an interface for Hiring Managers. Link.

Coupon Collector mathematical problem

• Mathematical vulgarization of Coupon Collector problem for a Medium article publication. Link.

Collaborative Filtering using FastAI library

• Movie recommendations model using deep learning and non deep learning methods. Link.

Image classification using FastAI library

• Image classification between bikes and trucks using deep learning models from FastIA or PyTorch libraries. Link.

Mobile games for Android and iOS

• Development of mobile games in C# using Unity, for Apple Store and Google Play Store. Integration of attribution and monetization.

Link.